We're out here at NFL owners meetings,
and I am joined by ESPN's Courtney
Cronin. Welcome back on our Vikings
channels. We love having you.
>> me. This is always something I look
forward to whenever we're at the combine
or we come out to owners meetings, and
it's my way of connecting back with the
Vikings fan base.
>> I know. We We have not forgotten about
you cuz we watch you on SportsCenter and
do all the ESPN uh stuff. So, I know you
have like a really good pulse on the
league in general. But, if we could just
focus on the NFC North, how do you feel
like between free agency, how that
played out, especially for the Bears who
I know [music] you cover? I think that
they lose a lot of veteran leadership,
whether it's D'Onta Foreman [music]
retiring, DJ Moore getting traded,
Tremaine Edmunds getting released. He
goes and signs with the New York Giants,
and Kevin Byard leaving in free agency
to go play for the New England Patriots.
[music] Like, this is a team that won 11
games in the regular season last year,
won its first playoff game in 15 years,
and they know they've got to start over
at ground zero. And that's Ben Johnson's
message to not only his players, it's
out there in the media. He does not want
to talk about 2025 anymore. I think a
lot of coaches
>> Yeah. have that same sort of approach,
[music]
but it shows you how quickly you can get
success, but how quickly you can lose it
because of what we've seen, the examples
of teams [music] around the NFL that
that's happened to, where it feels like
a pop-up one year, and you try to
sustain it, and you try to make the
right moves in free agency in the draft,
and then the next year is a step back.
So, the Bears are a team that just won
the division. They're trying to avoid
that regression when they finally got
things off on the right foot, in the
right track with Ben Johnson and Caleb
Williams. So, now it's how do they do
that? Because right now, after a quieter
free agency, but free agency where they
were still active, they brought in Kobe
Bryant, they brought in Garrett
Bradbury, who we all know well from his
time in Minnesota.
>> Um they're trying to figure out a way to
sustain the success without leaning on
what they did last year, but knowing
that the foundation is built.
>> Yeah. I mean, it just kind of feels like
the NFC North is always up for grabs
every single season. How do you see the
Vikings staying competitive in in that
division? Well, they did the right thing
by bringing in competition at
quarterback. We knew that they were
going to do that. This was all signs
pointing towards JJ McCarthy still here,
but he can't be the uncontested starter
going in. So, you resign a quarterback
in Carson Wentz, who played some pretty
important games last year in place of
McCarthy. But, most importantly, you
bring in Kyler Murray, who gets a chance
to revitalize his career. And I think
for somebody who has spoken so glowingly
not only about the organization and
growing up a Vikings fan,
>> [music]
>> but getting a chance now to work with
Kevin O'Connell. He has that reputation
that across the league, [music] these
young quarterbacks and I I still
consider Kyler, even though he signed a
second contract, I still consider him a
young quarterback. When you want to take
that next step, but you just don't feel
like you're in the right place to do it,
going somewhere else and working with a
coach who has shown a proven track
record of doing that, I think will will
yield benefits for both the team and the
player.
>> Okay. Well, I know that you covered the
Vikings for a while. You obviously have
a relationship with Executive Vice
President of Football Operations, Rob
Brzezinski. And And he's talking to the
media more, and our fans are kind of
hearing him more. I know.
>> More Rob. More Rob all the time. It's
always a positive thing. Um but, just
for just for fans who are just starting
to get to know him after you covered us
for so long, how like who is he as a
person, and what are you excited about
him getting this chance during the draft
to like really put a stamp on things?
>> There is no one who knows the Minnesota
Vikings better than Rob Brzezinski, the
institutional knowledge of someone who
has been with this team since the 1990s,
and seeing
all of it. Like, seeing the highs,
seeing the lows, seeing how they've
navigated different challenges before,
seeing how they've gone after the most
important position on any football team,
which is the quarterback, and the
lessons that they've learned along the
way in doing that. I'm excited for the
opportunity he's going to have here, and
I'm really eager to see what the draft
strategy is going to be because this is
a Vikings team spent a lot of money in
free agency a year ago. We know that the
results didn't necessarily yield the
type of success the team wishes it would
have had, but you've got somebody now
who has
like is the pulse on the whole team. He
knows everybody. I mean, the the The one
thing I will say about the Minnesota
Vikings that is more unique than any
other team that I've covered, you have
people in that personnel department who
have been in the trenches with Rob for
decades. That doesn't always happen
where it's for the a big part of it, the
bones of this staff were around for
previous regimes. And now that you have
somebody at the helm who is among the
most well-respected people in the NFL,
and we know how they feel about him in
Minnesota, I think it's going to be a
really good thing. I'm excited to see
what the future holds for him throughout
this draft process and also beyond it,
too.
>> I know. Beyond it, it's going to be an
interesting process. Thank you so much,
Courtney, for your insight. Really
appreciate it. Awesome seeing you. Enjoy
your rest of your time in Phoenix.